foreign
[Music]
what's the role of nutrition for both
preventing and beating covet 19.
nutrition related myths on protection
and treatment have been widely prevalent
in this pandemic and while there's no
diet that completely prevents infection
there are certainly dietary steps we can
take to minimize risk those with
healthier diets in general seem to
suffer less serious courses but this
appears to be an indirect benefit of
lower rates of obesity in pre-existing
medical conditions I mean that's great
but is there any diet that may have
Direct effects on the course of disease
or susceptibility to infection in the
first place well plant-based diets have
been shown to decrease the risk of
suffering from other respiratory
infections in fact plant-based
seminaries during the pandemic of 1918
appear to have been relatively spared
why might a plant-based diet help
vegetable nitrates concentrate in dark
green leafy vegetables can be used to
make nitric oxide which is part of our
lungs first line of defense against
infection they're also polyphenol
phytonutrients and plants that make
directly inhibit viral infection then
there are beneficial effects on our
microbiome which plays a key role in our
system-wide immune function fiber
containing foods facilitate more of a
symbiotic relationship with our gut bugs
whereas processed junk and animal foods
can have the opposite dysbiotic effect
fiber concentrated in whole plant Foods
is the single most anti-inflammatory
food component whereas saturated fat
concentrated in meat during junk is the
most pro-inflammatory food component and
so no surprise those consuming more
pro-inflammatory diets were at greater
risk of suffering a severe course and of
getting covid-19 in the first place up
to nearly 12 times the odds even after
taking into account bodyweight diabetes
and blood pressure
but this study only covered 60 coveted
patients how about 11
000 coveted patients diet Associated
inflammation increase the risk of
getting covid-19 infection suffering a
severe course and dying from the disease
might this help explain why the covet
death rates were 100 times lower in
Africa can a plant-based diet help
mitigate covid-19 let's find out in this
study of covid-19 illness severity in
the elderly in relation to vegetarian
versus non-vegetarian diets
statistically the non-vegetarians had up
to like 20 times the odds of suffering a
critically severe course of covid but
that was based on only nine vegetarians
now here a study of thousands of
Frontline healthcare workers across six
countries found those sitting
plant-based diets had 73 lower odds of
suffering a moderate or severe course of
covid-19 and even combined with
pescetarians who eat fish but no other
meat still had significantly lower odds
the biggest spread was between those
eating plant-based versus low carb
compared to plant-based healthcare
workers those eating low carb high
protein diets and nearly four times
greater odds of suffering a serious
infection
this may not seem surprising given that
many of the underlying risk factors for
covid-19 mortality obesity heart disease
high blood pressure type 2 diabetes can
be controlled or even reversed with
health in a plant-based diet and
lifestyle but the parent plant-based
protection went above and beyond
the greatly reduced risk was independent
of all those conditions the researchers
suggest that a healthy diet rich in
nutrient dense foods may be considered
for protection against severe covet 19.
the one food group most associated with
lower symptom severity and one
outpatient study was legumes followed by
grains the top sources of dietary fiber
the investigators suggests that the
anti-inflammatory effects of the short
chain fatty acids released by our
fiber-feeding good gut bugs may explain
the connection
the healthcare worker study enrolled a
few thousand people but Harvard
researchers collected data from nearly
600 000 participants using a plant-based
diet scoring system where you get points
for eating healthy plant foods but
points deducted for meat eggs junk and
dairy and indeed those scoring higher
not only had a significantly lower risk
of suffering a severe course of covid-19
but also significantly lower risk of
getting infected in the first place and
again this was after taking
comorbidities into account alongside
non-dietary risk factors such as
exercise and smoking bottom line
the best available evidence suggests
plant-based diets are beneficial in
directly reducing the risk of severe
cova-19 symptoms and the risk of
infection even independent of other
health related factors a more
Mediterranean style diet May reduce the
risk of infection by 22 percent while
even more plant-based diet may cut
infection risk in half
for dealing with long coven a
plant-based diet has been suggested
based on the abundance of data showing
positive associations of plant-based
diets with improved immune function
neurotransmitter balance pain and
inflammation reduction improve sleep and
mental health so in terms of Lifestyle
adjustments and long covet management
large-scale promotion of plant-based
eating may have the potential to improve
physical mental impacts but this has yet
to be put to the test there was a study
that suggested those who eat more
vegetables are less likely to end up
depressed and those who eat more nuts
beans and whole grains may end up less
depressed anxious and stressed after
coven whereas stress levels were
correlated with higher meat intake but
the only Interventional studies are like
this showing a detrimental impact on
high fat high sugar diets but that's in
Syrian hamsters though there's
definitely some unhappy hamster lungs on
the crappy diet
all in all adopting a healthy
plant-based diet may be a powerful tool
to decrease the risk of severe covid-19
and should be promoted as a public
health safety measure and what are the
side effects a delay in aging and
decreased disease maybe this is the
booster we need after all if real effort
had gone into encouraging and
incentivizing healthier diets and
Lifestyles we would not only have saved
many more lives from covid-19 but we
would also reduce future mortality from
all major causes of death
foreign